Guide to the Harris-Oliphant papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Harris-Oliphant Papers,
[ca. 1867]-1940
Harris, Thomas Lake, 1823-1906.
ca. 10,000 items (19 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078869
Biographical Note
American Christian mystic.
Laurence Oliphant (1829-1888) was a British writer and traveller.
Scope and Content
Letters written by and to Harris and his associate, Laurence Oliphant. In addition to the correspondence, these papers include manuscripts of books, miscellaneous biographical materials, and photographs.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 6 series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Diaries and Transcriptions
Series III: Writings
Series IV: Lawton & Schneider's Notes and Research Files
Series V: Miscellaneous
Series VI: Photographs
Subjects
Oliphant, Laurence, 1829-1888.; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940.; Schneider, Herbert Wallace, 1892-1984.; Lawton, George, 1900-1957.; Authors, English.; Christianity.ican.; Mysticism and literature.; Religion and literature.; Photoprints.; Mystics.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1943 M-43 Schneider, Herbert O. Gift
The collection was formed in part by the poet Edwin Markham, after whose death it passed to Prof. Herbert Schneider and George Lawton and was used in writing their biography of Harris and Oliphant, A PROPHET AND A PILGRIM.
Related Material
Collections related by provenance: Harris-Oliphant Papers at English Dept. of Wagner College, Staten Island. This collection duplicates Columbia holdings in part.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries I.1: Cataloged Correspondence
    - Laurence Oliphant To [?], London, 10 Feb. [n.y.], (3p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    - Laurence Oliphant To [?], London, 1 May [n.y.], (2p. (with three related items) a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    - Laurence Oliphant To Charles [?], London, 4 April [1865], (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
    - M[aria Campbell] (Mrs. Anthony) Oliphant To Mrs. Liddell, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2p. a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Subseries I.2: Arranged Correspondence
    - T.L. Harris, Mrs. Emily Harris, and Mrs. Jane Harris To [?], [n.p.], 1867-1892, (ca. 20 items, In 1 folder) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - T.L. Harris, Mrs. Emily Harris, and Mrs. Jane Harris To [?], [n.p.], 1893-1914, (ca. 25 items, In 1 folder) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - T.L. Harris and Mrs. Jane Harris To [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 10 items, In 1 folder) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Misc. Harris Material To [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 75 items, In 1 folder) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arthur A. Cuthbert To T.L. Harris and [?], [n.p.], 1879-1906, (ca. 15 items, In 1 folder) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Various writers (C-W) To Mr. and Mrs. T.L. Harris and [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 75 items, In 3 folder) (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
    - [?] To Mr. and Mrs. T.L. Harris and [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 75 items, In 3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
    - Edwin Markham To [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 15 items, In 1 folder) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - James Freeman To Edwin Markham, [n.p.], 1922-1931, (ca. 15 items, In 1 folder) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Robert M. Hart To Edwin Markham, [n.p.], 1914-1932, (ca. 50 items, In 1 folder) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Kanaye Nagasawa To Edwin Markham, [n.p.], 1920-1926, (ca.10 items, In 1 folder) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Various writers (C-S) To Edwin Markham and [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 100 items, In 1 folder) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Misc. Markham Material To [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 5 items, In 2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 6, 7)
    - Laurence and Alice Oliphant To Mr. and Mrs. William F. Cowper, [n.p.], 1867-17 Feb.1868, (ca. 75 items, In 1 folders) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Laurence and Alice Oliphant To Mr. and Mrs. William F. Cowper, [n.p.], 5 March 1868-30 June 1877, (ca. 100 items, In 1 folders) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Laurence and Alice Oliphant and [?] To [?], [n.p.], 1860-1880, (ca. 5 items, In 1 folders) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Laurence Oliphant To [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 30 items, In 1 folders) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Misc. Oliphant Material To [?], [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 50 items, In 1 folders) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series II: Diaries and Transcriptions
  This series comprises transcriptions of letters by various writers, diary entries by Thomas Lake Harris, dictations/sermons of Thomas Lake Harris, an epigram from Thomas Lake Harris, and a partial bibliography of Thomas Lake Harris works with table of contents.
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Transcriptions of Letters, [n.p.], 1878-1880, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Transcriptions of Letters, [n.p.], 1880-1881, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Transcriptions of Letters, [n.p.], 1881-1882, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Transcriptions of Letters, [n.p.], 1882-1885, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Transcriptions of Letters, [n.p.], 1885-1903, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Letters and Diary, [n.p.], 1899-1906, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Diary, [n.p.], 1896-1898, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Diary, [n.p.], 1898-1901, (1 bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Diary, [n.p.], 9 Sept [n.y.], (1 item, in 1 Folder) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Harris, Thomas Lake Sermon, [n.p.], 11 June 1887, (3 items, in 1 Folder) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series III: Writings
  - Subseries III.1: Articles, A-Z
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Mss., [v.p.], [v.d.] one dated 23 Sept 1878, (5 a.ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Advance of the Thinker: Divine Rest" - tms., ms.; "Approaching Judgement of the Colored Race" - ms.; The Artist Supreme" - ms.; An Autobiographic Sketch" - tms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (4 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Beginnings of the New Order" - ms.; The Bible: Its Weaknesses and its Power" - ms.; Bridal Love, the Keystone of the Arch" - tms.; "The Bridal Word" (in part) - ms.; "Building Order in the New Life" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (5 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Chastity, Poverty and Obedience---The Three Vital Principles of the Spiritual Evolution" - tms., ms.; "Christ is the Word of the Universe" - tms., ms.; "The Church Does not Build on the Divine Ground" - tms., ms.; "The Church Fights All New Revelations" - tms.; "The Church the Bride of the State" - tms., ms.; "The Concept of Christ Rejected by Christendom" - tms.; "Concept of the Word" (?) - ms.; "The Conflict Between the Upper and the Under Powers" - tms., ms.; "The Conflict of the Two Authorities" - tms., ms.; "Creeds Suppress God's Evolution" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (10 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Diary in Wales" - tms.; "The Divine Bible is in Man" - tms., ms.; "The Doctrine of Liberty" - ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (3 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Easter Lilies" - ms.; "Esoteric Buddhism: A Critique" - ms, [v.p.], [v.d.], (2 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Face---Not the Spirit---of History Changes" - tms., ms.; "The Fate of the False Religionists" - tms., ms.; "A Few Fragments" - tms., ms.; "Forces that Obstruct the Descent of the Luminous People" - tms., ms.; "Freedom from the Slavery of Labor" - tms.; "Freedom, Humility, and the Unborn Church" - tms., ms.; "The Functions of the True King" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (7 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Glimpse of the Kingdom Descended to Earth's Frontier" - tms., ms; "A Glimpse of the New Time" - tms., ms.; "A Glimpse of Woman's Difficult Problem" - tms. ms.; "Glimpses of Life in the New Time" - tms., ms.; "The Golden Mean" - ms.; "The [Greensim] Day" - ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (6 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Hell-Swamp Redeemed into a Paradise" - tms., ms.; "Hell the Parasite of Earth: Savior-Work Therein" - tms., ms.; "Hell the Parasite of Earth: The Angels" - tms., ms.; "Hints for the Order of the New Time" - tms., ms.; "Homes: New Forces: The Tree of Life" - tms.; "How Lost Souls are Saved" - ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (6 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Immense Problem of Society" - tms., ms.; "Is the Divine Word, a Book or a Man?" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (2 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Ladys Day Feb 8" - ms.; "Law as the Form of God" - ms.; "The Law of Isolation" - ms.; "The Law of the Lord's Descent into Earth" - tms., ms.; "The Law of the Separation of the Sexes" - tms.; "A Leaf from Eternity" - tms., ms.; "Lily's Song" - tms., ms.; "The Little Builders of the Body" - tms.; "Localities: March of Events" - ms.; "The Lord as the Warrior" - tms., ms.; "The Lord Dwells in all Pleases of Life" - tms., ms.; "The Lord Manifested as the Solar Man" - tms., ms.; "Lost Eden and the Law of Forgiveness" -tms., ms.; "The Lost Ideal of the People" - tms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (14 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Mankind Immersed in Stenches" - tms., ms.; "Marriage Mysteries" "It is now in order to make..." - tms., ms.; "Marriage Mysteries" "Woman in divine order..." - tms., ms.; "A Memorandum of Principles" - tms., ms.; "The Miracle of Love" - ms.; "More Words to Correspondents" - tms., ms.; "A Morning Talk" - ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (7 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The [Olean] Ideal" - ms.; "The Occult Events on the Brink of the New Time" - tms., ms.; "Occult San Francisco: Other Occult Tidings" - tms., ms.; "The Oneness of the Two Great Religions" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (4 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Preparation for the New Earth" - tms., ms.; "Provisional Organization in the New Time" - tms., ms.; "Private Property and Social Life in the Light of the Christ" - tms.; "Principles of Social Fraternity" - tms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (4 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Reserve of Royalty" - tms., ms.; "The Revival of the Memories" - tms., ms.; "The Rise of Arch-Natural Religion" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (3 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Sexes Need for a Season a Monastic Separation" - tms., ms.; "Shakerism as Seen from the Viewpoint of the New Life" - ms.; "Shakerism in the Unseen: Ann Lee in her Paradise" - tms., ms.; "A Sketch of Social Beginnings" - tms.; "The Social Sense the Soul of Solidarity" - tms., ms.; "Some Principles of the Divine Order" - tms., ms.; "Some Principles of the New Life" - tms., ms.; "Sources of Man's Life" - tms., ms.; "Spiritual Scientifics" - tms., ms.; "Steps to Physical Immortality" - tms., ms.; "Steps toward the New Life" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (11 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Theo-Socialism" - ms.; "Tidings from the Unseen" Chapter 1 - ms.; "The Tribunal of the Greater Crimes" - tms., ms.; "Trinities in God and Man" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (4 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Unconverting 'the Converted': Lifting Spirits out of the Fantasies of Churchianity" - tms., ms.; "Voices that Die into Echoes" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (2 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Wages and Other Problems in New Society" tms., ms.; "The Wisdom of the Adepts" - ms.; "A Word on Esoteric Buddhism" - tms.; "A Word on the Religions" - tms., ms.; "Words of Yessa" - tms., ms.; "Wrongs to Labor, with Hints for a New Order" - tms., ms., [v.p.], [v.d.], (6 ms., in 1 Folder) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Subseries III.2: Titled Prose A-Z
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Angels Striving Toward the Luminous", [n.p.], [n.d], (1 t.ms., 6 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["Ann Lee"], [n.p.], [n.d], (1 a.ms., 6 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Annunciation of the Son of Man", [n.p.], [n.d], (1 a.ms., 3 copies, ca. 462 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 3-5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Possible Titles for "The Bridal Word", [n.p.], [n.d], (1 a.ms., 1 page, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Bridal Word", [n.p.], [n.d], (1 t.ms., 3 versions, in 4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 2-5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Chapter from the Far Future", [n.p.], 2 May 1876, (1 a.ms., 11 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Conflict in Christendom", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 2 versions, 8 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 7, 8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Critique of Swedenborg", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 ms., 2 versions, ca. 57 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 9, 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Declarations of the Divine One-Twain", [n.p.], 1882, (1 t.ms., 92 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Diary of Occult Events: 1879", [n.p.], 1879, (1 t.ms., 244 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Discourse of Religion"; "The Avatar", [n.p.], 11 July 1902, (1 a.ms., ca. 64 pages, in 1 bound volume, In 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Dives and Lazarus: A Sermon", [n.p.], 19 Aug 1888, (1 a.ms., ca. 8 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Divine Renewel Must Reach into the Human Body and the Social Body", [n.p.], 8 March [n.y.], (2 ms., ca. 20 pages, in 2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 15, 16)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Doctrine of Liberty", [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 t.ms., 3 versions, ca. 33 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 17-19)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Doctrine of Property", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms. & carbons, 8 pages, in 2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 20, 21)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Door of Escape", [n.p.], 21 Apr 1877, (1 a.ms., ca. 20 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Earth Depends on Divine Victory in Hell", Linn Lilla, 21 May 1891, (1 a.ms., 2 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Elementaries", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 16 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Arcana of Christianity: Genesis - Vol II", Vinecliff, 1858, (3 copies & various sheets, 1 t.ms. & carbons, ca. 600 pages, In 4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 2-5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Arcana of Christianity: Matthew", Fountain Grove, 1858, (2 copies, 1 t.ms. & carbons, ca. 250 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 6, 7)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Arcana of Christianity: Matthew" - Various Sheets, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Artist is Supreme", [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 copies, 1 t.ms., 3 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 9, 10)
      [Version 3 located in Box 21, Folder 1]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Attempt to Blend the Races", [n.p.], 15 Sept [n.y.], (1 a.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A [sic] Author's Note of Introduction", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., 1 page, in 1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "B.G.", [n.p.], 24 Jan [n.y.], (1 a.ms., 9 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Bible: Its Weakness and its Power", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 37 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Book of O.I.", [n.p.], 1870, (1 t.ms. & carbons, ca. 100 pages, in 2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Doctrine of Property", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Earth's Sub-Human Parasites", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 9 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Esoteric Science", [n.p.], 4 Oct 1883, (1 a.ms, ca. 84 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Esoteric Science", [n.p.], 4 Apr 1885 - 29 July 1885, (1 a.ms, ca. 200 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Esoteric Science", [n.p.], 31 July 1885 - 6 Dec 1885, (1 a.ms, ca. 150 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Esoteric Science - Vol II", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 versions, 1 t.ms., ca. 750 pages, In 5 folders) (Box 8, Folder 4-8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Esoteric Science in Human History", Fountaingrove, 1884, (1 t.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Esoteric Wisdom [Science?]", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., ca. 200 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Fantasmal in Man", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss., & 1 set of carbons, ca. 70 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1, 2)
      [Version 3 located in Box 21, Folder 4.]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "First Book of the Christian Religion", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 56 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["First Esoteric"], [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., ca. 17 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "First Discourse", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 23 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["Foretells the Destruction"], [n.p.], 31 Oct 1878, (1 a.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Glance at Swedenborg", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., 5 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 6, 7)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Glimpse of Hell", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms & carbons, 8 pages, in 2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 8, 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Glimpses of Scoial and Sexual Order", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 7 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["Glories of the Future"], [n.p.], 13 Sept [n.y.], (1 a.ms., ca. 316 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "God as the Absolute", [n.p.], 14 June 1888, (1 a.ms., 2 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "God in Myriads of Manifestation", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The God-Quickened Universe", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 2 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Golden Child" - Part IV, [n.p.], 1878, (1 t.ms., 14 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Golden Mean", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss. & carbons, & 1 set of carbons, 51 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 16, 17)
      [Version 3 is located in Box 21, Folder 7]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Group of Principles", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 versions & carbons, 1 t.ms., ca. 70 pages, In 4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 18-21)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Heart Wants of London"; "Christ Incarnate"; "Liberty and Progress"; "Probably Grounds of Christian Union"; "The New church: Its Spirit, Scope and Mission"; "More Warnings Against Spiritism", [n.p.], [n.d.], (6 t.mss., 55 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Herald of Light" - Salutatory, [n.p.], [1857-1861], (1 t.ms., 13 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "How Souls are Saved", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms, 2 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["How the Lord is Found"], [n.p.], 29 July 1877, (1 a.ms, 12 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "In a Garden of Eros", [n.p.], [26 Nov 1878], (1 a.ms, & 1 t.ms., ca. 300 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 24, 25)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Invasion of Heaven", [n.p.], 1884-5, (1 t.ms, ca. 30 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Judgement of the Heavens", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms, 325 pages, in 3 folders) (Box 21, Folder 10-12)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Kingdom in Organization", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms, & 1 t.ms., ca. 74 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1, 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Last Pages from the Diary", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss., ca. 30 pages, in 2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 13, 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Law as the Form of God", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss., 3 pages, in 2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 3)
      [Version 2 is located in Box 21, Folder 15]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Law of Prayer", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss., & 1 set of carbons, ca. 15 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 4, 5)
      [Version 3 is located in Box 21, Folder 16]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Letter to a Seeker in Retreat", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 3 t.mss., ca. 7 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 6-8)
      [Version 4 is located in Box 21, Folder 17.]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Life Origins", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 20 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Light on Divine Brotherhood", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 28 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Luminious Life" - Various Drafts, [n.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 1200 pages a.ms & t.ms., in 10 folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Lunarians", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 74 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Man and the Immorality of his Dreams", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 3 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Man Sunken in the Dream Sphere of the Animal", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss., & 1 set of carbons, ca. 154 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 12, 13)
      [Version 3 is located in Box 21, Folder 19.]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Memorabilia of the Heavenly Life", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 85 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Millenial Age", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 75 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Miracle of Love", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss. & carbon, & 1 set of carbons, 3 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 16)
      [Version 3 is located in Box 21, Folder 20]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Morning Talk", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss., & 1 set of carbons, 21 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 17, 18)
      [Version 3 is located in Box 21, Folder 21.]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Movements in the Occult", [n.p.], 17 May 1878, (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., ca. 70 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 19, 20)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Nature", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 20 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The New Kingdom of Labor", [n.p.], 22 Nov 1877, (1 a.ms., ca. 33 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["The New Life in Doctrine"] - Epitome, [n.p.], 7 July 1896, (1 a.ms., 5 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["The New Man Androgynous"], [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., 3 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The New Order Just Tho Some May Suffer.. ."; "The Sweep-Out of Human Rubbish.. .", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., 14 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Occultisms", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 35 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Our Lord Suffering in His Present Passion for Humanity", [n.p.], 12 Mar [n.y.], (1 a.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Parish of the Priest", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 2 t.mss., & 1 set of carbons, ca. 50 pages, in 4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 28-30)
      [Version 4 is located in Box 21, Folder 22.]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Path into the New Life", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 40 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Path of Ascent, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 1 page, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Politics? Old and New", [n.p.], 1877, (1 t.ms., 18 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Preaching the Gospel: Sowing the God-Seed", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 34)